Ignacio **Gómez**

Software Engineer

About

Av. Luis Thayer Ojeda 855 Apt. 504 Providencia, Santiago Chile

ignacio.gomeze@icloud.com

http://relative.cl linkedin://gomezignacio

Languages

native spanish intermediate english

Hard skills

software development, clean architecture, agile, RESTful, git

Soft skills

leadership, teamwork, constructive attitude, people management, business orientation

Introduction

I'm Software Engineer. I started as iOS developer 7 years ago then I have been mobile team's manager since 2017 to now. My main interests are software development, software architecture, leadership, team success, mobile new trends and technology in general.

Experience

2021-now Software Engineer Manager - MACH (BCI)

Manager of mobile team at MACH, in charge of Android and iOS teams. their recruitment and professional development. I had worked on making

a strategy in long term for the team, define profiles, set goals and challenge to them to do their best to make a great and high performance team. Because fast growth of the company the main goal is working on scaling and sturdiness of projects, ensuring long-term robustness.

2017-2020 Head of Mobile - Yapo.cl (Adevinta)

Santiago, Chile

Santiago, Chile

Lead of mobile team at Yapo.cl, in charge of Android and iOS teams, their recruitment and professional development. The main goal was keep the motivation and high performance. Technically, my biggest challenge in this position has been developing an strategy to do all the refactoring process on legacy projects (Android and iOS), and, at the same time, maintaining the development that the new projects and business needs, beside the other technical improvements. I have worked together with many teams from many countries and coordinate the implementation and development of several global projects.

2016-2017 iOS Developer - Yapo.cl (Adevinta)

Santiago, Chile

Maintenance and development of new projects for Yapo's iOS app, and change the way of understanding the product and the developments, with the view if the business. Yapo is one of the biggest classified sites and with more visits in Chile, and it's part of Adevinta (at that time we were part of Schibsted, that also included the media business). This group represent a big global company with many classified sites around the world.

2015-2016 iOS Developer - VITALE

Santiago, Chile

Development and maintenance of the Vitale iOS app. I worked with sync between app and a smartband by bluetooth, besides a sport social network like Instagram.

2015 Speaker - GECHS

Santiago, Chile

Speaker of iOS application development course.

2013-2014 iOS Developer - Playontag

Santiago, Chile

Development and maintenance of Playontag iOS app (iPhone and iPad), Chilean Museum of Pre-Columbian Art iOS app (iPhone) and Mapuche Museum of Cañete iOS app (iPad).

- 2013-2014 **Teacher Federico Santa María Technical University** Valparaíso, Chile Workshop of introduction to iOS development.
- 2011-2012 **Professional Internship TINET Informatics Solutions** Viña del Mar, Chile Development of iOS app (iPhone and iPad), focused on the stock market, for an important Chilean banking company.
 - 2010 Internship as Software Engineer Akzio Consultants Santiago, Chile ETL workflows development with Oracle Warehouse Builder and PL/SQL scripts with tool Toad for Oracle, for an important Chilean banking company.

Education

2008 - 2014 Federico Santa María Technical University

Valparaíso, Chile

Computer Science

Thesis title: "Model of notifications to users according to context and profile for the social network Playontag"

Interests

Keeping learning about new technologies, architectures, improving my technical and soft skills, software development, and always do my best to reach my goals. I'm a very passionate person, I enjoy so much my work especially when I'm doing things that cause a positive impact on many other people.

Other data and activities

I'm father, I'm a passionate about photography, I do triathlon and I'm an outdoor sports lover. I have done 4 Ironman 70.3 and several other triathlons, running and trail running races (more information here). My longest race to now was a trail running called Patagonia Run, where I ran 70K in the middle of beautiful mountains in the south of Argentina in a little more than 12 hours, and I'm going to do my first full Ironman next year. Having a balanced life, between family, sport, hobbies and work, is very important to me.